<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guidelines on DSC Community</title>
    <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guidelines on DSC Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 the dsccommunity.org contributors.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started as a Contributor</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of guides on the Internet that will show different aspects of what is described here, but this article will focus on a simple way to get started using the workflow we use for DSC modules and DSC resources within the DSC Community.
 After you read through this guide, then please continue with the guide Contributor.
 Table of Contents  Create free GitHub account Install Visual Studio Code Install Visual Studio Code PowerShell Extension Install Git Configure Git Install PowerShell Module posh-git Install GitVersion Clone repository from GitHub Forking a repository on GitHub Adding the fork as a remote in the local repository Making changes and pushing them to the fork Make changes to an existing pull request of yours Switch between local working branches Delete a branch  Create free GitHub account Create a free GitHub account by browsing to GitHub and clicking on the Sign up button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in contributing to the DSC Community.
There are several ways you can contribute.
 You can submit an issue to report a bug or to request an improvement. You are encourage to take part in discussions around an issue or pull request. You may review pull requests. You may send in a pull request to improve the DSC modules by adding a new DSC resource, fixing issues in existing DSC resources, improve the CI pipeline, or updating documentation around the DSC modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/maintaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/maintaining/</guid>
      <description>Security To be maintainer you must have 2FA enabled on accounts that give you access to DSC Community resources, for example your GitHub account and the account that access DSC Community Azure DevOps organization.
Breaking Changes See Breaking Changes
Review Not yet written.
Merging code Only merge code that passes status checks, have been reviewed, and where all the review comments have be resolved and approved.
As a maintainer you are allowed to review and merge your own code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/style-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/style-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>The Style Guidelines can be found in its own section Style Guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/testing-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/testing-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>General Rules  Tests are written using Pester. Preferably use the concept of test-driven development when writing tests. Each DSC module should contain the following Test folder structure:  tests |---Unit |---Integration  The tests\Unit folder must contain a Test Script for each DSC Resource in the DSC Module with the filename DSC_&amp;lt;ResourceName&amp;gt;.Tests.ps1. The tests\Integration folder should, whenever possible, contain a Test Script for each DSC Resource in the DSC Module with the filename DSC_&amp;lt;ResourceName&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administration</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/administration/</guid>
      <description>Security To be administrator you must have 2FA enabled on accounts that give you access to DSC Community resources, for example your GitHub account and the account that access DSC Community Azure DevOps organization.
GitHub Create GitHub repository To create a new GitHub repository in the DSC Community organization, browse to https://github.com/dsccommunity and click on New.
All repositories should always be added with MIT licensing.
 NOTE: To be able create repositories you must be an owner of the GitHub DSC Community organization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>