<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSC Community</title>
    <link>https://dsccommunity.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DSC Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 the dsccommunity.org contributors.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dsccommunity.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Next Community Call 2023-04-05</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</guid>
      <description>Next call will be on Wednesday, April 5th, at 12 PM PST
Join the call Join using the Microsoft Teams app
Or click here to browse the list of available dial-in numbers to find one that is local to your region
Conference ID: 503 431 76#
Agenda TBD. Suggestions for talks are welcomed, we have Call for speakers open.
Community questions Submit your questions, or raise them directly in the call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Configuration Management</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/configmgt/future-of-config-mgt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:44:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/configmgt/future-of-config-mgt/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s good to make sure we understand the world in which DSC evolves, so I thought of writing this post below. Unfortunately, the future is not something we can predict, so this is just a personal opinion, which I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful.
Configuration Management evolution Some like to classify different configuration management models, but I prefer to show them as an evolution of similar principles, that happened with the evolution of technology and principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin Story</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community/origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 15:36:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community/origin-story/</guid>
      <description>The DSC Resource Kit A lot has changed since the creation of the DSC Resource Kit back in 2013—the PowerShell/DSC Team initiative was created to seed the DSC Ecosystem.
The intention then was to illustrate the capabilities of DSC, and solve realistic configuration scenarios to build a community of users. The team had been developing the resources and publishing them as the PowerShell Team in TechNet Gallery, long before the PowerShell Gallery existed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Desired State Configuration</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/help/what-is-dsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 10:56:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/help/what-is-dsc/</guid>
      <description>As per the official documentation, Desired State Configuration (DSC) is a management platform in PowerShell.
It is built around different components:
 DSC DSL: The Domain Specific Language of DSC with the Configuration keyword. DSC LCM: The Local Configuration Manager (LCM), that can be seen as the agent enacting the configurations on the managed nodes. DSC Resources: A rich ecosystem of modules exposing a declarative and idempotent interface to imperative code configuring resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ownership of DSC Resources</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 15:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community/ownership/</guid>
      <description>Goal and purpose Previously owned by the DSC Team, and more specifically by Katie, the DSC Resources are now owned by the DSC Community: a collective of Open Source maintainers getting together to improve the Resources, their quality and the practices around DSC.
The main purpose is to handle better the increased community contributions, and remove hindrance to improvements by spreading the load on a Committee, and giving more privileges to the maintainers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an Article</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/create-an-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 12:41:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/create-an-article/</guid>
      <description>Creating the md file is easy, but you might want to double check how it will render on the website. To do so, we recommend you to install Hugo (using Chocolatey it&amp;rsquo;s just a choco install hugo) and test what you create.
But when you have installed hugo, forked the dsccommunity.org, and cloned your fork locally, you can generate a post from the template, from the source directory:
 C:\src\dsccommunity.org &amp;gt; hugo new blog/your-title-in-lowercase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Standards</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/standards/</guid>
      <description>Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment include:
 Using welcoming and inclusive language Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences Gracefully accepting constructive criticism Focusing on what is best for the community Showing empathy towards other community members  Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include:
 The use of sexualized language or imagery and unwelcome sexual attention or advances Trolling, insulting/derogatory comments, and personal or political attacks Public or private harassment Publishing others&#39; private information, such as a physical or electronic address, without explicit permission Other conduct which could reasonably be considered inappropriate in a professional setting  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started as a Contributor</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of guides on the Internet that will show different aspects of what is described here, but this article will focus on a simple way to get started using the workflow we use for DSC modules and DSC resources within the DSC Community.
After you read through this guide, then please continue with the guide Contributor, especially the section Understand the coding workflow.
Table of Contents  Quick steps Create free GitHub account Install Visual Studio Code Install Visual Studio Code PowerShell Extension Install Git Configure Git Install PowerShell Module posh-git Install GitVersion Clone repository from GitHub Forking a repository on GitHub Adding the fork as a remote in the local repository Making changes and pushing them to the fork Make changes to an existing pull request of yours Switch between local working branches Delete a branch  Quick steps Here are some quick steps to get started building and testing a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Files</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/markdown-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/markdown-files/</guid>
      <description>Line length not longer than 80 characters Rows longer than 80 characters should be split into multiple lines where appropriate. This helps make it easier for reviewers to make review comments and for the contributors to see where the requested changes are (without scrolling). It is also easier to see the lines in split view mode when the lines don&amp;rsquo;t wrap on the screen. It will also improve the readability when using git diff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSC is Dead</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/dsc-is-dead-long-live-dsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/dsc-is-dead-long-live-dsc/</guid>
      <description>Hi PowerShell and DSC folks!
I wanted to share the PSConfEU session Michael and myself have recorded on DSC and Guest Configuration.
There will be a live Q&amp;amp;A on the Wednesday 3rd of June at 6PM CEST (9AM Pacific Time), so make sure you have watched and submit any further question. Tune-in as early as Tuesday 2nd of June 5PM CEST to watch the live Opening and Keynote with Tobias, Jeffrey Snover and Joey Aiello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSC Community Committee</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community/committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community/committee/</guid>
      <description>The following is an explanation of what the DSC Committee is attempting to help with, and how we are trying to help the community.
Come and chat with us if you would like to discuss how we can improve and build a better community!
Members 
Katie is the owner of the Resource Kit at Microsoft and has steered its direction over the years. She is also an active member of the Engineering team at Microsoft looking after all things DSC as well as Azure Guest Configuration, and can bridge the communication between the new products and features leveraging DSC and the DSC Community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Future for Dsc</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/help/what-future-for-dsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 11:35:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/help/what-future-for-dsc/</guid>
      <description>Despite the few &amp;ldquo;DSC Planning Updates&amp;rdquo; written by Michael Greene (Program Manager for DSC, and DSC Community Committee member), there are still misunderstandings by the community with regards to the directions Microsoft is taking for DSC and its ecosystem.
Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain what we understand from the DSC Community.
Former plans &amp;amp; realignment Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s DSC Team, about a year and an half ago, was working on a new version of the LCM component of the DSC Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Responsibilities</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>Project maintainers are responsible for clarifying the standards of acceptable behavior and are expected to take appropriate and fair corrective action in response to any instances of unacceptable behavior.
Project maintainers have the right and responsibility to remove, edit, or reject comments, commits, code, wiki edits, issues, and other contributions that are not aligned to this Code of Conduct, or to ban temporarily or permanently any contributor for other behaviors that they deem inappropriate, threatening, offensive, or harmful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in contributing to the DSC Community.
There are several ways you can contribute.
 You can submit an issue to report a bug or to request an improvement. You are encourage to take part in discussions around an issue or pull request. You may review pull requests. You may send in a pull request to improve the DSC modules by adding a new DSC resource, fixing issues in existing DSC resources, improve the CI pipeline, or updating documentation around the DSC modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/general/</guid>
      <description>Correct File Encoding Make sure all files are encoded using UTF-8 (not UTF-8 with BOM), except mof files which should be encoded using ASCII. You can use ConvertTo-UTF8 and ConvertTo-ASCII to convert a file to UTF-8 or ASCII.
Descriptive Names Use descriptive, clear, and full names for all variables, parameters, and functions. All names must be at least more than 2 characters. No abbreviations should be used.
Bad:
$r = Get-RdsHost Bad:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintainers</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community/maintainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community/maintainers/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of the current maintainers of DSC modules in the DSC Community. If you wish to be a maintainer in a module, please either contact a maintainer of the module, or a member of the committee. If you are a maintainer and feel you no longer have the time to put in and want to stop being maintainer then please send in a PR to update this list, or contact a member of the committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scope</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/scope/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/scope/</guid>
      <description>This Code of Conduct applies both within project spaces and in public spaces when an individual is representing the project or its community. Examples of representing a project or community include using an official project e-mail address, posting via an official social media account, or acting as an appointed representative at an online or offline event. Representation of a project may be further defined and clarified by project maintainers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/maintaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/maintaining/</guid>
      <description>Security To be maintainer you must have 2FA enabled on accounts that give you access to DSC Community resources, for example your GitHub account and the account that access DSC Community Azure DevOps organization.
Breaking Changes See Breaking Changes
Review Not yet written.
Merging code Only merge code that passes status checks, have been reviewed, and where all the review comments have be resolved and approved.
As a maintainer you are allowed to review and merge your own code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitespace</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/whitespace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/whitespace/</guid>
      <description>Indentation For all indentation, use 4 spaces instead of tabs. There should be no tab characters in the file unless they are in a here-string.
No Trailing Whitespace After Backticks Backticks should always be directly followed by a newline
Newline at End of File All files must end with a newline, see StackOverflow.
Newline Character Encoding Save newlines using CR+LF instead of CR. For interoperability reasons, we recommend that you follow these instructions when installing Git on Windows so that newlines saved to GitHub are simply CRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/enforcement/</guid>
      <description>Enforcement Instances of abusive, harassing, or otherwise unacceptable behavior may be reported by contacting the project team at dsccommunity@outlook.com. All complaints will be reviewed and investigated and will result in a response that is deemed necessary and appropriate to the circumstances. The project team is obligated to maintain confidentiality with regard to the reporter of an incident. Further details of specific enforcement policies may be posted separately.
Project maintainers who do not follow or enforce the Code of Conduct in good faith may face temporary or permanent repercussions as determined by other members of the project&amp;rsquo;s leadership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/functions/</guid>
      <description>Function Names Use Pascal Case Function names must use PascalCase. This means that each concatenated word is capitalized.
Bad:
function get-targetresource { # ... } Good:
function Get-TargetResource { # ... } Function Names Use Verb-Noun Format All function names must follow the standard PowerShell Verb-Noun format.
Bad:
function TargetResourceGetter { # ... } Good:
function Get-TargetResource { # ... } Function Names Use Approved Verbs All function names must use approved verbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/style-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/style-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>The Style Guidelines can be found in its own section Style Guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Questions</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/common_questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/common_questions/</guid>
      <description>For answers to common questions about this code of conduct, see https://www.contributor-covenant.org/faq</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameters</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/parameters/</guid>
      <description>Correct Format for Parameter Block  An empty parameter block should be displayed on its own line like this: param (). A non-empty parameter block should have the opening and closing parentheses on their own line. All text inside the parameter block should be indented once. Every parameter should include the [Parameter()] attribute, regardless of whether the attribute requires decoration or not. A parameter that is mandatory should contain this decoration: [Parameter(Mandatory = $true)].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/testing-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/testing-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>General Rules  Tests are written using Pester. Preferably use the concept of test-driven development when writing tests. Each DSC module should contain the following Test folder structure:  tests |---Unit |---Integration  The tests\Unit folder must contain a Test Script for each DSC Resource in the DSC Module with the filename DSC_&amp;lt;ResourceName&amp;gt;.Tests.ps1. The tests\Integration folder should, whenever possible, contain a Test Script for each DSC Resource in the DSC Module with the filename DSC_&amp;lt;ResourceName&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administration</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/guidelines/administration/</guid>
      <description>Security To be administrator you must have 2FA enabled on accounts that give you access to DSC Community resources, for example your GitHub account and the account that access DSC Community Azure DevOps organization.
GitHub Create GitHub organization Team Repository Maintainer Team Each repository that is created in a DSC Community GitHub organization should have at least one team for maintainers. This team should be a child team of the GitHub organization team Maintainers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribution</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/attribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/code_of_conduct/attribution/</guid>
      <description>This Code of Conduct is adapted from the Contributor Covenant, version 1.4, available at https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variables</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/variables/</guid>
      <description>Variable Names Use Camel Case Variable names should use camelCase.
Bad:
function Write-Log { $VerboseMessage = &amp;#39;New log message&amp;#39; Write-Verbose $VerboseMessage } Bad:
function Write-Log { $verbosemessage = &amp;#39;New log message&amp;#39; Write-Verbose $verbosemessage } Good:
function Write-Log { $verboseMessage = &amp;#39;New log message&amp;#39; Write-Verbose $verboseMessage } Script, Environment and Global Variable Names Include Scope Script, environment, and global variables must always include their scope in the variable name unless the &amp;lsquo;using&amp;rsquo; scope is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/general-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/general-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Although adopting the best practices is optional, doing so will help improve the quality of the DSC resource module.
Note: Modules that aim to meet the High Quality Resource Module standards must also implement the best practices wherever possible.
Avoid Using ard coded Computer Name Using hard coded computer names exposes sensitive information on your machine. Use a parameter or environment variable instead if a computer name is necessary. This comes from this PS Script Analyzer rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Functions</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/calling-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/calling-functions/</guid>
      <description>Avoid Cmdlet Aliases When calling a function use the full command not an alias. You can get the full command an alias represents by calling Get-Alias.
Bad:
ls -File $root -Recurse | ? { @(&amp;#39;.gitignore&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;.mof&amp;#39;) -contains $_.Extension } Good:
Get-ChildItem -File $root -Recurse | Where-Object -FilterScript { @(&amp;#39;.gitignore&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;.mof&amp;#39;) -contains $_.Extension } Avoid Invoke-Expression Invoke-Expression is vulnerable to string injection attacks. It should not be used in any DSC resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Functions</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/writing-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/writing-functions/</guid>
      <description>Avoid Default Values for Mandatory Parameters Default values for mandatory parameters will always be overwritten, thus they are never used and can cause confusion.
Bad:
function Get-Something { param ( [Parameter(Mandatory = $true)] [String] $Name = &amp;#39;My Name&amp;#39; ) ... } Good:
function Get-Something { param ( [Parameter(Mandatory = $true)] [String] $Name ) ... } Avoid Default Values for Switch Parameters Switch parameters have 2 values - there or not there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Conversation</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community/contact/</guid>
      <description>The #DSC Channel The community gathers in the Virtual PowerShell User Group #DSC channel, which is an open &amp;amp; instant messaging chat room for all DSC related questions, discussions, and collaboration.
The PowerShell channels are bridged between Discord and Slack, so you can use either service, via the apps or websites.
The Virtual PowerShell User Group contains more than just the #DSC channel: there are also channels covering topics related to PowerShell, DevOps as well as many other and practices and technologies, so you may also join them too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dsc Resource Functions</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/dsc-resource-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/dsc-resource-functions/</guid>
      <description>Return a Hashtable from Get-TargetResource Bad:
Good:
Return a Boolean from Test-TargetResource Bad:
Good:
Avoid Returning Anything From Set-TargetResource Bad:
Good:
Define Get-TargetResource, Set-TargetResource, and Test-TargetResource for Every DSC Resource Bad:
Good:
Get-TargetResource should not contain unused non-mandatory parameters The inclusion of a non-mandatory parameter that is never used could signal that there is a design flaw in the implementation of the Get-TargetResource function. The non-mandatory parameters that are used to call Get-TargetResource should help to retrieve the actual values of the properties for the resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifest</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/manifest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/manifest/</guid>
      <description>Avoid Using Deprecated Manifest Fields Bad:
Good:
Ensure Manifest Contains Correct Fields Bad:
Good:
Do not use NestedModules to export shared commands Since we don&amp;rsquo;t use the RootModule key in the module manifest, we should not use the NestedModules key to add modules that export commands that are shared between resource modules.
Normally, a single list in the RootModule key, can restrict what is exported using the cmdlet Export-ModuleMember. Since we don&amp;rsquo;t use the RootModule key we can&amp;rsquo;t restrict what is exported, so every nested module will export all the commands (or all the commands restricted by Export-ModuleMember in that individual nested module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localization</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/localization/</guid>
      <description>In each resource folder there should be at least one localization folder for english language &amp;lsquo;en-US&amp;rsquo;. Add other localization folders as appropriate, the correct folder name can be found by running Get-UICulture on the node that has a UI culture installed that the strings are being built for. There is also the list of Available Language Packs for Windows.
In each localization folder there should be a PowerShell data (.psd1) file named &amp;lsquo;DSC_&amp;lt;ResourceName&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pester Tests</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/pester-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/styleguidelines/pester-tests/</guid>
      <description>Capitalized Pester Assertions Pester assertions should all start with capital letters. This makes code easier to read.
Bad:
it &amp;#39;Should return something&amp;#39; { get-targetresource @testParameters | should -be &amp;#39;something&amp;#39; } Good:
It &amp;#39;Should return something&amp;#39; { Get-TargetResource @testParameters | Should -Be &amp;#39;something&amp;#39; } Assertion Messages Start with Should Pester assertions should always start with the word &amp;lsquo;Should&amp;rsquo;. This is to ensure the test results read more naturally as well as helping to indentify assertion messages that aren&amp;rsquo;t making assertions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023-02-22 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2023-02-22-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2023-02-22-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Community presentation &amp;ldquo;WinGet and DSC Resources&amp;rdquo; presented by Demetrius Nelon.
DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  ConfigMgrCBDsc v4.0.0 - New resources CMClientSettingsComputerRestart and CMHierarchySetting   Preview  SqlServerDsc v16.1.0-preview0017 - SQL Server 2022 support + New public commands in preparation for new class-based resources UpdateServicesDsc v1.3.0-preview0003 - Various fixes and changes StorageDsc v5.1.0-preview0003 - support to use disk SerialNumber as a disk identifer    Tooling modules that have been released recently  Releases  None.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023-01-11 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2023-01-11-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2023-01-11-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Community presentation &amp;ldquo;Microsoft365DSC is a DSC module like any other, or is it?&amp;quot; presented by Yorick Kuijs.
How is Microsoft365DSC different compared to &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; DSC modules? What challenges did we have to overcome? And how we made it even more awesome!
DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  WebAdministrationDsc v4.1.0   Preview  SqlServerDsc v16.1.0-preview0008 - A lot of cleanup of existing code since last time, been in preview since last Community Call, we should release CertificateDsc v6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-11-30 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-11-30-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-11-30-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda  Floor is open for the community - questions or if someone want to show something  DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SharePointDsc v5.3.0 (support SharePoint subscription Edition) xCredSSP 1.4.0 (moved to new pipeline to solve semantic versioning)   Preview  WebAdministrationDsc v4.1.0-preview0001 (fix bug that broke WebApplication after module rename) ComputerManagementDsc v8.6.0-preview0004 (Computer now handles joining to domain when computer account already exist) SqlServerDsc v16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-10-19 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-10-19-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-10-19-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Community Presentation  Constantin Hager: Azure Automation DSC and the Azure VM DSC Extension. How do they work together?  In this presentation you will see how to deploy Azure Automation State configuration (DSC). We will deploy DSC Configurations and assign them to Azure VMs . I will also show how you can deploy a DSC Configuration without Azure Automation State Configuration (DSC).
Everything will all happen with Azure DevOps and a CI / CD Process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-05-04 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-05-04-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-05-04-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity  PowerShell DevOps Global Summit 2022  Special Guests &amp;amp; Announcement The PowerShell Desired State Configuration module is now open sourced!!!:
 Jodi Boone, Program Manager for Guest Configuration Jason Helmick, Program Manager for PowerShell (including PowerShell DSC) Michael Greene, Principal Program Manager for PowerShell and Guest Configuration  Code contributions are not considered at this time, except for tests. Issues and discussions are welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-09-07 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-09-07-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-09-07-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity  Machine Config is GA Updates on DSC Docs by Sean and Mikey.  Special Guests &amp;amp; Announcement  Jodi Boone, Program Manager for Guest Configuration Jason Helmick, Program Manager for PowerShell (including PowerShell DSC) Michael Greene, Principal Program Manager for PowerShell and Guest Configuration  Also presenting the Microsoft technical writers:
 Sean Wheeler Mikey Lombardi Mike F. Robbins  Tooling modules that have been released recently  Releases  Sampler v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-03-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-03-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Quick update on activity   DscCommunity.org pipeline is fixed (using a workaround) - still waiting on the fix that makes us use the latest version of Hugo.
  Upcoming talks to PS Summit NA and PSConfEU
  Gael demo&amp;rsquo;d Sampler.DscPipeline
  Jodi Boone, new Program Manager for Guest Configuration
  Demo of Test-Kitchen
  Do the community have any activity updates?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-16 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-02-16-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-02-16-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Quick update on activity  DscCommunity.org pipeline is fixed (using a workaround) - still waiting on the fix that makes us use the latest version of Hugo. Upcoming talks to PS Summit NA and PSConfEU Gael demo&amp;rsquo;d Sampler.DscPipeline  DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SChannelDsc v1.3.0 ConfigMgrCBDsc v3.0.0 SharePointDsc v5.0.0   Preview releases  SqlServerDsc v16.0.0-preview0003 SharePointDsc v5.1.0-preview0003    Tooling modules that have been released recently  Releases  Sampler v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-11-17 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-11-17-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-11-17-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Quick update on activity  Azure DevOps has removed the build worker Ubuntu 16.04. Repos using it in the pipeline (well, all of them) need to change to &amp;lsquo;ubuntu-latest&amp;rsquo;. Example: https://github.com/dsccommunity/SqlServerDsc/pull/1733/files Azure Devops has deprecated the build worker Windows Server 2016 (&amp;lsquo;windows-2016&amp;rsquo;). Repos using that for unit test or integration tests need to move to &amp;lsquo;windows-2019&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;windows-2022&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;windows-latest&amp;rsquo; before March 2022. This may cause problems with assuring support on older operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-10-06 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-10-06-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-10-06-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda  Steve and Andrew from the PowerShell team join us to discuss the recent changes to PowerShell DSC.  Quick update on activity  xPSDesiredStateConfiguration has now be moved to auto documentation, using GitHub Repository Wiki. (though need another merge for it to publish) xExchange  We unblocked contributors in xExchange. Working on fixing the pipeline that blocking releases (PR is in review) Since Mike no longer have time to maintain xExchange the community need a new maintainer for that repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-08-25 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-08-25-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-08-25-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity  DscResource.DocGenerator&amp;rsquo;s Wiki generation  now handles properties in parent classes now generate docs for composite resources   DscResource.Common and FileSystemDsc tests runs using Pester 5.  DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SharePointDSC 4.7.0   Preview releases  SqlServerDsc 15.2.0-preview0004 NetworkingDsc 9.0.0-preview0001 SharePointDSC 4.8.0-preview0002 DnsServerDsc 3.0.1-preview0002 ConfigMgrCBDsc 2.1.0-preview0003    Tooling modules that have been released recently  Releases  DscResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-02 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-06-02-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-06-02-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Main Session: Guest Configuration Michael Greene, Program Manager for Azure Policy Guest Configuration, and Gael Colas will present what Guest Configuration is, and what you can do with it.
In this presentation we&amp;rsquo;ll demo ways you can create your own packages leveraging DSC Resources, test them whether on Windows or Linux, and see how you can use them through Azure Policy.
Quick update on activity Updated blog post on how to enable code coverage for built-modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-04-21 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-04-21-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-04-21-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity Updated blog post on how to enable code coverage for built-modules. https://dsccommunity.org/blog/add-codecov-support-to-repository/
DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  xFailOverCluster 1.16.0 xDnsServer 2.0.0 (DEPRECATED -&amp;gt; Move to DnsServerDsc v3.0.0 once released) SharePointDsc v4.6.0   Preview releases (many due to adding support for code coverage)  SharePointDsc v4.6.1-preview0003 StorageDsc v5.1.0-preview0001 ComputerManagementDsc v8.5.0-preview0001 xPSDesiredStateConfiguration v9.2.0-preview0004 SqlServerDsc v15.2.0-preview0002 DFSDsc v4.5.0-preview0001 WSManDsc v3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-03-10 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-03-10-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-03-10-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity Rename default branch Work in progress to rename default branch to main. See blog post Steps to rename master branch to main for a DSC Community resource how to update the pipeline to support the rename.
DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SharePointDsc v4.5.1 SqlServerDsc v15.1.1 xFailOverCluster v1.15.0   Preview releases (many due to renaming the default branch)  ActiveDirectoryDsc v6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-01-27 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-01-27-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-01-27-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity Move to new pipeline Currently active repositories have moved to the new pipeline. Holding off on the rest of the repositories, migrating as needed.
Rename default branch Work in progress to rename default branch to main. See blog post Steps to rename master branch to main for a DSC Community resource how to update the pipeline to support the rename.
Finished so far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-12-16 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-12-16-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-12-16-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes  Quick update on activity: DSC resource modules that have been released recently News recap Class Based DSC Resources &amp;ldquo;Reasons&amp;rdquo; in DSC Resources Compare-DscParameterState and JeaDsc Next Community Call (27th of January)  Suggestions for talks are welcomed.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-09-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-09-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-09-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes  Quick update on activity:  Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  xBitlocker xDatabase   In progress  xCredSSP   New modules  None   Completed  DfsDsc FileContentDsc xSystemSecurity ComputerManagementDsc ActiveDirectoryDsc NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc SQLServerDsc WSManDsc xFailOverCluster xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xWebAdministration GPRegistryPolicyDsc UpdateServicesDsc ActiveDirectoryCSDsc xExchange FileSystemDsc xBitlocker xDatabase       DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SqlServerDsc 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-08-12 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-08-12-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-08-12-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes   Quick update on activity:
 Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  FSRMDsc JeaDsc   In progress  None   New modules  ConfigMgrCBDsc   WIP modules (no DSC resources yet)  AzureDevOpsDsc (maintainer Ryan Yates) GitHubEnterpriseDsc (maintainer Ryan Yates)   Modules not yet converted but with fairly recent activity (seen in AppVeyor)  DscResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-07-01 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-07-01-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-07-01-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes  Quick update on activity:  Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  DfsDsc FileContentDsc   In progress  FSRMDsc   New modules Modules not yet converted but with PR activity within last 4 months (seen in AppVeyor)  JeaDsc DscResource.Analysis xBitlocker   Completed  xSystemSecurity ComputerManagementDsc ActiveDirectoryDsc NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc SQLServerDsc WSManDsc xFailOverCluster xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xWebAdministration GPRegistryPolicyDsc UpdateServicesDsc ActiveDirectoryCSDsc xExchange FileSystemDsc       Resources that have been released recently  Releases Preview release Modules    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-05-20 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-05-20-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-05-20-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes   Presentation by Bartek Bielawski: Class Based DSC Resources from the trenches Meeting recording
  Women in PowerShell/DevOps Virtual Event (Registration)
  Open discussion - SqlServerDsc: Renaming resources that contain &amp;lsquo;Server&amp;rsquo; https://github.com/dsccommunity/SqlServerDsc/issues/1540
  Quick update on activity:
 Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  iSCSIDsc StorageDsc SecurityPolicyDsc SChannelDsc xDscDiagnostics   In progress  FSRMDsc   New modules  SChannelDsc (from Yorick)   Modules not yet converted but with PR activity within last 4 months (seen in AppVeyor)  JeaDsc DfsDsc DscResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-04-08 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-04-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-04-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording Waiting to be published
  --Agenda  Quick update on activity Presentation by Raimund Andre: Less code in resource with Test-DscParameterState    Migration to Continuous Delivery Process:
  Completed since last call
 OfficeOnlineServerDsc xDhcpServer xHyper-V xDnsServer    Completed
 xSystemSecurity ComputerManagementDsc ActiveDirectoryDsc NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc SQLServerDsc WSManDsc xFailOverCluster xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xWebAdministration GPRegistryPolicyDsc UpdateServicesDsc ActiveDirectoryCSDsc xExchange OfficeOnlineServerDsc    In progress:  Others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-02-26 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-02-26-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-02-26-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording Meeting recording   Agenda   What to do about resources that have no maintainer?
 Problem: without a maintainer the resource can&amp;rsquo;t be updated to the new continuous delivery process so can&amp;rsquo;t be released.  Options:  Archive? Leave as is? Other options?        What to do about resources that have a maintainer but the update to the continuous delivery process is not proceeding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-01-22 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-01-22-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-01-22-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording Meeting recording   Agenda   Welcome to New Community Committee Member.
  What to do if a PR doesn&amp;rsquo;t get reviewed in a reasonable time frame?
 Minimum time before a maintainer may merge a PR without a review is 24 hours. Recommended time to wait before maintainer can merge a PR without a review is 72 hours. PRs to fix broken pipelines or high risk security issues are exempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-12-04 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-12-04-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-12-04-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Agenda   Demo of automation and status update (continued)
 DscResource.AnalyzerRules DscResource.Test Sampler &amp;amp; AzureDevOps    DSC Community Maintainers, what should you do?
 Accept GitHub Invitation (or tell us if you did not receive it) Consider making your DSC Community membership public Use the DSC Community&amp;rsquo;s Teams for communication (discussions) Consider updating your GitHUb picture &amp;amp; Bio (we use it to display on the website) Try doing code reviews even outside of your repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-10-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-10-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-10-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording The recording of the community call, with the result of the DSC Survey is available on YouTube:   Notes   Quick intro of automation as introduced during last call I&amp;rsquo;ve done a video since to show the basic template automation     Shared results of DSC survey (watch the video for details)
  More maintainers for the DSC resources needed? We agreed we needed to be more active in our search for maintainers, but we also need to make the &amp;ldquo;Contributor Funnel&amp;rdquo; more attractive and working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-09-11 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-09-11-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-09-11-notes/</guid>
      <description>Read the DSC Resource Kit Release September 2019 Blog post, on PowerShell&amp;rsquo;s blog.
Resources released  ActiveDirectoryDsc ComputerManagementDsc (BREAKING CHANGE - ScheduleTask) DFSDsc (Fix to get the examples to be published) NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc (might not be released) StorageDsc WmiNamespaceSecurityDsc (former WmiNamespaceSecurity) xDnsServer xFailOverCluster xHyper-V xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xRemoteDesktopSessionHost xSCSMA xWebAdministration  Deprecated  xRemoteDesktopAdmin (moved to ComputerManagementDsc) (No PR to deprecate yet) xPendingReboot (moved to ComputerManagementDsc)  Should leaving unsupported OS be treated as breaking change No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a breaking change but it should be clearly noted in release notes when conscious decision is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-07-31 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</guid>
      <description>The community call was recorded, you can listen here.
  Agenda Resource Kit August 2019 See resources to be released below.
DSC Community Logo The logo will be published on https://dsccommunity.org with a license granting everyone to use it.
DSC Community Organization Gael talked about the new organization (listen back to the recording when it is available, and you can read more about it here https://dsccommunity.org/community/)
DSC Community Committee Read more about it here https://dsccommunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-06-19 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released There are 7 modules on track for release on Wednesday June 26:
 CertificateDsc NetworkingDsc PSDscResources SharePointDsc SqlServerDsc (BREAKING CHANGE) xActiveDirectory xDnsServer  Discussions   Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call)
  Ben Gelens not able to maintain xHyper-V anymore
  DSC Community Logo
  Waffle board has closed, Migrated to GitHub board, but not great</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-05-08 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released  TBC  Discussions  Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call) Celebrating new maintainers:  Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Jason Patton &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xDnsServer Nehru Ali &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Johan Ljunggren &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xSmbShare (this resource is being moved to ComputerManagementDsc) Jason Ryberg &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory, ActiveDirectoryCSDsc and xAzure Mike Beggs &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; NetworkingDsc and xDhcpServer Ryan Christman &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory Jan-Hendrik Peters &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory and xSCVMM Chase Wilson &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xAzure and xFirefox   Waffle board will be closing, still looking into a replacement Moving off gitter to PoshCode slack: the #dsc channel in either Slack or Discord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert tests to Pester 5 for a DSC Community repository</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/convert-tests-to-pester5-for-dsc-community-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/convert-tests-to-pester5-for-dsc-community-repository/</guid>
      <description>This blog post will guide you on how to convert existing tests in a DSC Community DSC resource module repository using a new pattern that is better suited for Pester 5.
You are welcome to share any comments or issues you having around this process in the Discord or Slack #DSC channel.
This previous blog post Converting tests to Pester 5 covered an early version of Pester 5 and the patterns that should be used have been improved (and are still being improved).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Based DSC Resource only proposal</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/class-based-dsc-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/class-based-dsc-resources/</guid>
      <description>Recently, the PowerShell team announced plans to create a new JSON-based schema so that eventually PowerShell Desired State Configuration (DSC) could get rid of its MOF/CIM dependencies, and the PowerShell code base could remove its deprecated Management Interface (MI) implementation (Microsoft.Management.Infrastructure.CimProperty, Microsoft.Management.Infrastructure.CimInstance and so on&amp;hellip;).
The suggested change was only for DSC Resources schema, and no changes to MOF compilations was announced for now. Removing the CIM/MI/MOF code and dependency is definitely an overarching goal for PowerShell, but it won&amp;rsquo;t happen overnight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting tests to Pester 5</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/converting-tests-to-pester5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 05:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/converting-tests-to-pester5/</guid>
      <description>If you have any questions or suggestions around this blog post then please reach out to @johlju in the Virtual PowerShell User Group #DSC channel.
UPDATE: To convert tests for a repository in DSC Community also see the blog Convert tests to Pester 5 for a DSC Community repository
Pester Pester, the famous DSL and module in the PowerShell community, is used throughout the DSC modules and their common modules to ensure we maintain quality for all new contributions by testing any addition and verify they work with the rest of the code to avoid regression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Code Coverage Support to Repository</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/add-codecov-support-to-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 19:17:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/add-codecov-support-to-repository/</guid>
      <description>This assumes the repository is using the pattern from the Sampler project. Also make sure you have updated the repository to the latest pipeline.
Table of Contents  Introduction Not building module, just copying files Building whole or part of module Code coverage for multiple jobs  Introduction With the release of Pester v4.10 it is now possible to upload the Pester generated JoCoCo file. The same file is used to upload code coverage to both Azure Pipelines and to Codecov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DscResource.Common functions in a DSC module</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/use-dscresource-common-functions-in-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 15:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/use-dscresource-common-functions-in-module/</guid>
      <description>What This article will explain the steps needed to use a version of the DscResource.Common module that has been released to the PowerShell Gallery.
The module DscResource.Common currently has 7 cmdlets.
 Get-LocalizedData New-InvalidArgumentException New-InvalidOperationException New-NotImplementedException New-InvalidResultException New-ObjectNotFoundException Test-DscParameterState  Why Historically, these functions have been duplicated into many DSC resource modules. This has resulted in duplication of effort in maintaining them as well as drift in the code base and feature set with some fixes not being included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to convert a module for continuous delivery</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/convert-a-module-for-continuous-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 12:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/convert-a-module-for-continuous-delivery/</guid>
      <description>You are welcome to share any comments or issues you having around this process in the Discord or Slack #DSC channel.
Before you start, here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of what the new CI looks like:    NOTE: The build is running on Linux in the CI pipeline to be able to support cross-platform DSC resources, so that makes all paths case-sensitive! Have that in mind when updating paths and folders in the configuration files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use DSC Logging</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/how-to-use-dsc-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 16:37:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/how-to-use-dsc-logging/</guid>
      <description>The Local Configuration Manager (LCM) in PowerShell Desired State Configuration (DSC) logs its deployment progress and errors on several places. The most commonly known location is the event log, where errors are logged in the log: Applications and Services Logs \ Microsoft \ Windows \ Desired State Configuration \ Operational
This log contains various events that were generated during a DSC job, it is however less useful to track the progress of a running job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realizing maintenance windows with DSC</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/dsc-maintenance-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 18:11:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/dsc-maintenance-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Since 2017 I have been involved in a number of DSC projects in medium to very large enterprises. It has not been easy to implement DSC for a number of reasons. For some companies, the reason why DSC was not an option is the lack of support for maintenance windows. DSC runs whenever an internal timer expires. This is fine for some enterprises but not for all. This article summarizes the ideas and technical implementation I have worked on with two large enterprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to rename master branch to main for a DSC Community resource</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/convert-master-to-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/convert-master-to-main/</guid>
      <description>You are welcome to share any comments or issues you having around this process in the Discord or Slack #DSC channel.
On the 1st of October 2020, GitHub announced that the default branch name for new repositories was changing from master to main.
This post describes the process required to rename master branch to main for a DSC community resource module. It is up to individual maintainers if they wish to rename master to main on their repositories</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating repo with Sampler.GitHubTasks</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/updating-sampler-github-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/blog/updating-sampler-github-tasks/</guid>
      <description>A lot of improvements have been made to the Sampler module and templates in the last couple of weeks, and it&amp;rsquo;s a (small) breaking change that needs a manual update to your repos.
We knew for a long time that Sampler was needed some refactor to make it more testable and maintainable. A while ago, we took some shortcuts we knew we&amp;rsquo;d have to refactor at some point, and we finally did it!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
