<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Calls on DSC Community</title>
    <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Calls on DSC Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 the dsccommunity.org contributors.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Community Call 2020-01-22</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</guid>
      <description>Next call will be on Wednesday, January 22nd, at 12 PM PST
This community call is not at the normally scheduled date/time. Please use this file to add to your calendar.
Agenda   Welcome to New Community Committee Member.
  DSC Community: What to do if a PR doesn&#39;t get reviewed in a reasonable time frame?
 What is the reasonable time frame? Proposal: that a DSC resource maintainer is allowed to merge PRs that did not get a review after 7 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-12-04 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-12-04-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-12-04-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Agenda   Demo of automation and status update (continued)
 DscResource.AnalyzerRules DscResource.Test Sampler &amp;amp; AzureDevOps    DSC Community Maintainers, what should you do?
 Accept GitHub Invitation (or tell us if you did not receive it) Consider making your DSC Community membership public Use the DSC Community&#39;s Teams for communication (discussions) Consider updating your GitHUb picture &amp;amp; Bio (we use it to display on the website) Try doing code reviews even outside of your repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-10-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-10-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-10-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording The recording of the community call, with the result of the DSC Survey is available on YouTube:   Notes   Quick intro of automation as introduced during last call I&#39;ve done a video since to show the basic template automation     Shared results of DSC survey (watch the video for details)
  More maintainers for the DSC resources needed? We agreed we needed to be more active in our search for maintainers, but we also need to make the &amp;ldquo;Contributor Funnel&amp;rdquo; more attractive and working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-09-11 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-09-11-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-09-11-notes/</guid>
      <description>Read the DSC Resource Kit Release September 2019 Blog post, on PowerShell&#39;s blog.
Resources released  ActiveDirectoryDsc ComputerManagementDsc (BREAKING CHANGE - ScheduleTask) DFSDsc (Fix to get the examples to be published) NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc (might not be released) StorageDsc WmiNamespaceSecurityDsc (former WmiNamespaceSecurity) xDnsServer xFailOverCluster xHyper-V xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xRemoteDesktopSessionHost xSCSMA xWebAdministration  Deprecated  xRemoteDesktopAdmin (moved to ComputerManagementDsc) (No PR to deprecate yet) xPendingReboot (moved to ComputerManagementDsc)  Should leaving unsupported OS be treated as breaking change No, it&#39;s not a breaking change but it should be clearly noted in release notes when conscious decision is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-07-31 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</guid>
      <description>The community call was recorded, you can listen here.
  Agenda Resource Kit August 2019 See resources to be released below.
DSC Community Logo The logo will be published on https://dsccommunity.org with a license granting everyone to use it.
DSC Community Organization Gael talked about the new organization (listen back to the recording when it is available, and you can read more about it here https://dsccommunity.org/community/)
DSC Community Committee Read more about it here https://dsccommunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-06-19 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released There are 7 modules on track for release on Wednesday June 26:
 CertificateDsc NetworkingDsc PSDscResources SharePointDsc SqlServerDsc (BREAKING CHANGE) xActiveDirectory xDnsServer  Discussions   Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call)
  Ben Gelens not able to maintain xHyper-V anymore
  DSC Community Logo
  Waffle board has closed, Migrated to GitHub board, but not great</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-05-08 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released  TBC  Discussions  Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call) Celebrating new maintainers:  Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Jason Patton &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xDnsServer Nehru Ali &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Johan Ljunggren &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xSmbShare (this resource is being moved to ComputerManagementDsc) Jason Ryberg &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory, ActiveDirectoryCSDsc and xAzure Mike Beggs &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; NetworkingDsc and xDhcpServer Ryan Christman &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory Jan-Hendrik Peters &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory and xSCVMM Chase Wilson &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xAzure and xFirefox   Waffle board will be closing, still looking into a replacement Moving off gitter to PoshCode slack: the #dsc channel in either Slack or Discord.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>