<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Calls on DSC Community</title>
    <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Calls on DSC Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 the dsccommunity.org contributors.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Community Call 2019-09-11</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Agenda  Feel free to send a PR to this file if there&amp;rsquo;s something you&amp;rsquo;d like to add to the agenda  Resources to be released TBC
Discussions Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call)
Talk to us on Virtual PowerShell User Group #DSC channel. For information on how to join, see https://dsccommunity.org/community/contact/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-07-31 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</guid>
      <description>The community call was recorded, and these notes will be updated with a link to the call once published.
Agenda Resource Kit August 2019 See resources to be released below.
DSC Community Logo The logo will be published on https://dsccommunity.org with a license granting everyone to use it.
DSC Community Organization Gael talked about the new organization (listen back to the recording when it is available, and you can read more about it here https://dsccommunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-06-19 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released There are 7 modules on track for release on Wednesday June 26:
 CertificateDsc NetworkingDsc PSDscResources SharePointDsc SqlServerDsc (BREAKING CHANGE) xActiveDirectory xDnsServer  Discussions  Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call) Ben Gelens not able to maintain xHyper-V anymore DSC Community Logo Waffle board has closed, Migrated to GitHub board, but not great Talk to us on PoshCode slack: the #dsc channel in either Slack or Discord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-05-08 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released  TBC  Discussions  Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call) Celebrating new maintainers:  Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Jason Patton &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xDnsServer Nehru Ali &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Johan Ljunggren &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xSmbShare (this resource is being moved to ComputerManagementDsc) Jason Ryberg &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory, ActiveDirectoryCSDsc and xAzure Mike Beggs &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; NetworkingDsc and xDhcpServer Ryan Christman &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory Jan-Hendrik Peters &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory and xSCVMM Chase Wilson &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xAzure and xFirefox  Waffle board will be closing, still looking into a replacement Moving off gitter to PoshCode slack: the #dsc channel in either Slack or Discord.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>