<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Calls on DSC Community</title>
    <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Calls on DSC Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2019 the dsccommunity.org contributors.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Next Community Call 2022-05-04</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/next_call/</guid>
      <description>Next call will be on Wednesday, May 4th, at 12 PM PST
Join the call Join using the Microsoft Teams app
Or click here to browse the list of available dial-in numbers to find one that is local to your region
Conference ID: 503 431 76#
Discussions Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call)
We are also available on the Virtual PowerShell User Group #DSC channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-03-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-03-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Quick update on activity   DscCommunity.org pipeline is fixed (using a workaround) - still waiting on the fix that makes us use the latest version of Hugo.
  Upcoming talks to PS Summit NA and PSConfEU
  Gael demo&amp;rsquo;d Sampler.DscPipeline
  Jodi Boone, new Program Manager for Guest Configuration
  Demo of Test-Kitchen
  Do the community have any activity updates?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-16 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-02-16-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2022-02-16-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Quick update on activity  DscCommunity.org pipeline is fixed (using a workaround) - still waiting on the fix that makes us use the latest version of Hugo. Upcoming talks to PS Summit NA and PSConfEU Gael demo&amp;rsquo;d Sampler.DscPipeline  DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SChannelDsc v1.3.0 ConfigMgrCBDsc v3.0.0 SharePointDsc v5.0.0   Preview releases  SqlServerDsc v16.0.0-preview0003 SharePointDsc v5.1.0-preview0003    Tooling modules that have been released recently  Releases  Sampler v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-11-17 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-11-17-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-11-17-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Quick update on activity  Azure DevOps has removed the build worker Ubuntu 16.04. Repos using it in the pipeline (well, all of them) need to change to &amp;lsquo;ubuntu-latest&amp;rsquo;. Example: https://github.com/dsccommunity/SqlServerDsc/pull/1733/files Azure Devops has deprecated the build worker Windows Server 2016 (&amp;lsquo;windows-2016&amp;rsquo;). Repos using that for unit test or integration tests need to move to &amp;lsquo;windows-2019&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;windows-2022&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;windows-latest&amp;rsquo; before March 2022. This may cause problems with assuring support on older operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-10-06 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-10-06-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-10-06-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda  Steve and Andrew from the PowerShell team join us to discuss the recent changes to PowerShell DSC.  Quick update on activity  xPSDesiredStateConfiguration has now be moved to auto documentation, using GitHub Repository Wiki. (though need another merge for it to publish) xExchange  We unblocked contributors in xExchange. Working on fixing the pipeline that blocking releases (PR is in review) Since Mike no longer have time to maintain xExchange the community need a new maintainer for that repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-08-25 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-08-25-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-08-25-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity  DscResource.DocGenerator&amp;rsquo;s Wiki generation  now handles properties in parent classes now generate docs for composite resources   DscResource.Common and FileSystemDsc tests runs using Pester 5.  DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SharePointDSC 4.7.0   Preview releases  SqlServerDsc 15.2.0-preview0004 NetworkingDsc 9.0.0-preview0001 SharePointDSC 4.8.0-preview0002 DnsServerDsc 3.0.1-preview0002 ConfigMgrCBDsc 2.1.0-preview0003    Tooling modules that have been released recently  Releases  DscResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-02 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-06-02-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-06-02-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Main Session: Guest Configuration Michael Greene, Program Manager for Azure Policy Guest Configuration, and Gael Colas will present what Guest Configuration is, and what you can do with it.
In this presentation we&amp;rsquo;ll demo ways you can create your own packages leveraging DSC Resources, test them whether on Windows or Linux, and see how you can use them through Azure Policy.
Quick update on activity Updated blog post on how to enable code coverage for built-modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-04-21 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-04-21-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-04-21-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity Updated blog post on how to enable code coverage for built-modules. https://dsccommunity.org/blog/add-codecov-support-to-repository/
DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  xFailOverCluster 1.16.0 xDnsServer 2.0.0 (DEPRECATED -&amp;gt; Move to DnsServerDsc v3.0.0 once released) SharePointDsc v4.6.0   Preview releases (many due to adding support for code coverage)  SharePointDsc v4.6.1-preview0003 StorageDsc v5.1.0-preview0001 ComputerManagementDsc v8.5.0-preview0001 xPSDesiredStateConfiguration v9.2.0-preview0004 SqlServerDsc v15.2.0-preview0002 DFSDsc v4.5.0-preview0001 WSManDsc v3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-03-10 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-03-10-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-03-10-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity Rename default branch Work in progress to rename default branch to main. See blog post Steps to rename master branch to main for a DSC Community resource how to update the pipeline to support the rename.
DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SharePointDsc v4.5.1 SqlServerDsc v15.1.1 xFailOverCluster v1.15.0   Preview releases (many due to renaming the default branch)  ActiveDirectoryDsc v6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-01-27 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-01-27-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2021-01-27-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Agenda Quick update on activity Move to new pipeline Currently active repositories have moved to the new pipeline. Holding off on the rest of the repositories, migrating as needed.
Rename default branch Work in progress to rename default branch to main. See blog post Steps to rename master branch to main for a DSC Community resource how to update the pipeline to support the rename.
Finished so far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-12-16 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-12-16-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-12-16-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes  Quick update on activity: DSC resource modules that have been released recently News recap Class Based DSC Resources &amp;ldquo;Reasons&amp;rdquo; in DSC Resources Compare-DscParameterState and JeaDsc Next Community Call (27th of January)  Suggestions for talks are welcomed.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-09-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-09-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-09-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes  Quick update on activity:  Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  xBitlocker xDatabase   In progress  xCredSSP   New modules  None   Completed  DfsDsc FileContentDsc xSystemSecurity ComputerManagementDsc ActiveDirectoryDsc NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc SQLServerDsc WSManDsc xFailOverCluster xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xWebAdministration GPRegistryPolicyDsc UpdateServicesDsc ActiveDirectoryCSDsc xExchange FileSystemDsc xBitlocker xDatabase       DSC resource modules that have been released recently  Releases  SqlServerDsc 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-08-12 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-08-12-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-08-12-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes   Quick update on activity:
 Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  FSRMDsc JeaDsc   In progress  None   New modules  ConfigMgrCBDsc   WIP modules (no DSC resources yet)  AzureDevOpsDsc (maintainer Ryan Yates) GitHubEnterpriseDsc (maintainer Ryan Yates)   Modules not yet converted but with fairly recent activity (seen in AppVeyor)  DscResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-07-01 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-07-01-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-07-01-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes  Quick update on activity:  Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  DfsDsc FileContentDsc   In progress  FSRMDsc   New modules Modules not yet converted but with PR activity within last 4 months (seen in AppVeyor)  JeaDsc DscResource.Analysis xBitlocker   Completed  xSystemSecurity ComputerManagementDsc ActiveDirectoryDsc NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc SQLServerDsc WSManDsc xFailOverCluster xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xWebAdministration GPRegistryPolicyDsc UpdateServicesDsc ActiveDirectoryCSDsc xExchange FileSystemDsc       Resources that have been released recently  Releases Preview release Modules    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-05-20 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-05-20-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-05-20-notes/</guid>
      <description>Recording   Notes   Presentation by Bartek Bielawski: Class Based DSC Resources from the trenches Meeting recording
  Women in PowerShell/DevOps Virtual Event (Registration)
  Open discussion - SqlServerDsc: Renaming resources that contain &amp;lsquo;Server&amp;rsquo; https://github.com/dsccommunity/SqlServerDsc/issues/1540
  Quick update on activity:
 Migration to Continuous Delivery Process (GitHub Board):  Completed since last call  iSCSIDsc StorageDsc SecurityPolicyDsc SChannelDsc xDscDiagnostics   In progress  FSRMDsc   New modules  SChannelDsc (from Yorick)   Modules not yet converted but with PR activity within last 4 months (seen in AppVeyor)  JeaDsc DfsDsc DscResource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-04-08 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-04-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-04-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording Waiting to be published
  --Agenda  Quick update on activity Presentation by Raimund Andre: Less code in resource with Test-DscParameterState    Migration to Continuous Delivery Process:
  Completed since last call
 OfficeOnlineServerDsc xDhcpServer xHyper-V xDnsServer    Completed
 xSystemSecurity ComputerManagementDsc ActiveDirectoryDsc NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc SQLServerDsc WSManDsc xFailOverCluster xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xWebAdministration GPRegistryPolicyDsc UpdateServicesDsc ActiveDirectoryCSDsc xExchange OfficeOnlineServerDsc    In progress:  Others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-02-26 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-02-26-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-02-26-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording Meeting recording   Agenda   What to do about resources that have no maintainer?
 Problem: without a maintainer the resource can&amp;rsquo;t be updated to the new continuous delivery process so can&amp;rsquo;t be released.  Options:  Archive? Leave as is? Other options?        What to do about resources that have a maintainer but the update to the continuous delivery process is not proceeding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-01-22 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-01-22-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2020-01-22-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording Meeting recording   Agenda   Welcome to New Community Committee Member.
  What to do if a PR doesn&amp;rsquo;t get reviewed in a reasonable time frame?
 Minimum time before a maintainer may merge a PR without a review is 24 hours. Recommended time to wait before maintainer can merge a PR without a review is 72 hours. PRs to fix broken pipelines or high risk security issues are exempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-12-04 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-12-04-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-12-04-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Agenda   Demo of automation and status update (continued)
 DscResource.AnalyzerRules DscResource.Test Sampler &amp;amp; AzureDevOps    DSC Community Maintainers, what should you do?
 Accept GitHub Invitation (or tell us if you did not receive it) Consider making your DSC Community membership public Use the DSC Community&amp;rsquo;s Teams for communication (discussions) Consider updating your GitHUb picture &amp;amp; Bio (we use it to display on the website) Try doing code reviews even outside of your repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-10-23 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-10-23-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-10-23-notes/</guid>
      <description>How to join
Recording The recording of the community call, with the result of the DSC Survey is available on YouTube:   Notes   Quick intro of automation as introduced during last call I&amp;rsquo;ve done a video since to show the basic template automation     Shared results of DSC survey (watch the video for details)
  More maintainers for the DSC resources needed? We agreed we needed to be more active in our search for maintainers, but we also need to make the &amp;ldquo;Contributor Funnel&amp;rdquo; more attractive and working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-09-11 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-09-11-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-09-11-notes/</guid>
      <description>Read the DSC Resource Kit Release September 2019 Blog post, on PowerShell&amp;rsquo;s blog.
Resources released  ActiveDirectoryDsc ComputerManagementDsc (BREAKING CHANGE - ScheduleTask) DFSDsc (Fix to get the examples to be published) NetworkingDsc SharePointDsc (might not be released) StorageDsc WmiNamespaceSecurityDsc (former WmiNamespaceSecurity) xDnsServer xFailOverCluster xHyper-V xPSDesiredStateConfiguration xRemoteDesktopSessionHost xSCSMA xWebAdministration  Deprecated  xRemoteDesktopAdmin (moved to ComputerManagementDsc) (No PR to deprecate yet) xPendingReboot (moved to ComputerManagementDsc)  Should leaving unsupported OS be treated as breaking change No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a breaking change but it should be clearly noted in release notes when conscious decision is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-07-31 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-07-31-notes/</guid>
      <description>The community call was recorded, you can listen here.
  Agenda Resource Kit August 2019 See resources to be released below.
DSC Community Logo The logo will be published on https://dsccommunity.org with a license granting everyone to use it.
DSC Community Organization Gael talked about the new organization (listen back to the recording when it is available, and you can read more about it here https://dsccommunity.org/community/)
DSC Community Committee Read more about it here https://dsccommunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-06-19 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-06-19-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released There are 7 modules on track for release on Wednesday June 26:
 CertificateDsc NetworkingDsc PSDscResources SharePointDsc SqlServerDsc (BREAKING CHANGE) xActiveDirectory xDnsServer  Discussions   Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call)
  Ben Gelens not able to maintain xHyper-V anymore
  DSC Community Logo
  Waffle board has closed, Migrated to GitHub board, but not great</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-05-08 Notes</title>
      <link>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 23:35:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsccommunity.org/community_calls/2019-05-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>Resources to be released  TBC  Discussions  Topics or questions from the community (welcome at any point during the call) Celebrating new maintainers:  Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Jason Patton &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xDnsServer Nehru Ali &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Brian Wilhite &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xPendingReboot Johan Ljunggren &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xSmbShare (this resource is being moved to ComputerManagementDsc) Jason Ryberg &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory, ActiveDirectoryCSDsc and xAzure Mike Beggs &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; NetworkingDsc and xDhcpServer Ryan Christman &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory Jan-Hendrik Peters &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xActiveDirectory and xSCVMM Chase Wilson &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; xAzure and xFirefox   Waffle board will be closing, still looking into a replacement Moving off gitter to PoshCode slack: the #dsc channel in either Slack or Discord.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
